Anand Punera

UdhamSinghNagar, Uttarakhand, 262308 +917415157982 anand.c.punera@gmail.com

Summary

Experienced software development Engineer having worked on Server side development for over 4 years. More than 5 years of experience in software development. Actively looking for an opportunity to work with a good software development team. Open to work on any relevant technology.

Education

National
Institute of
Technology,
Raipur
B-Tech in Computer
Science and Engineering

Raipur, Chhattisgarh Graduated May 2015

Completed Computer Science courseworks and multiple projects as part of Computer Science and Engineering, Bachelor of Technology programme at National Institute of Technology, Raipur.

Teaching and Mentoring Assistant at National Institute of Technology, Raipur for junior students from June 2014 - Dec 2014

Employment History

Hewlett Packard Enterprise, Bengaluru

Research & Development Engineer August 2015 - July 2017

Implemented key features like Notifications for Cloud Service Automation(Subscription Modification flows). Worked on integrating Liquibase (Version Control for database Schema) to simplify and enable tracking of the database schema changes. Implemented HotFixManager service using Node.js for the customers to

track the Hotfixes (Emergency Patches). Maintaining the entire CLOUD SERVICE AUTOMATION (CSA) Enterprise product.

Technology: Java, Spring framework, sql, Git, Linux, MS SQLServer, Postgres SQLServer, mysql, REST, node.js, nedb, etc

Amazon Development Centre

Aug 2017 - Oct 2018

Software Development Engineer

Worked as part of Amazon Echo Devices Software team. Got the opportunity to work on fireOs (android) framework layer, Amazon Alexa skills and application development for several key applications for devices of Amazon Echo family. Also worked on OOBE for Amazon Echo Show and echo spot.

Learned about clean code and best practices in OOPs, Object Oriented Analysis and Design.

Also got the opportunity to design and build features end to end.

Won the award in the Most customer ready category in Amazon internal Hackathon.

Tech Stack: java, http, android, aws, etc

Gameskraft Technologies Pvt Ltd

Bangalore, Karnataka

Senior Software Engineer

Nov 2018 - March 2020

Worked as a senior member of the backend tech team of Fantasy Sports project **Gamezy** (www.gamezy.com). Given the scale and the high availability requirements, Microservices architecture was used for the project.

Designed and developed the back-end services from scratch namely leaderboard service, team management service, Fixture service, User Service, api gateway on node.js, Bonus And Funds Manager service, etc.

Effectively used third party services like firebase, clevertap to capture user events. Extensively used kafka messaging queue, redis distributed caching, hazelcast, aws services, etc.

Tech Stack: java, spring boot, REST, mysql, aws, kafka, redis, hazelcast distributed cache

DrinkPrime

Bangalore, Karnataka

Senior Software Development Engineer consultant

March 2020 - August 2020

worked as a senior backend developer on designing and coding drinkprime application backend. Designed and Developed key features in the order service.

Tech Stack: java, spring boot, REST, mysql, aws, wordpress, etc.

Sep 2020 - Feb 2021

Bangalore, Karnataka

Senior Software Development Engineer consultant

Worked on Delivery Service (delivery lifecycle management team), help center and other critical microservices. Developed the Outside Order Support component.

Tech Stack: GoLang, REST, dynamo db, aws, kafka, redis.

VIDA Identity Management

Bangalore, Karnataka

Senior Software Development Engineer consultant

Working on the Identity service, Operations support System, Self Service portal, etc services.

Worked on key features like Face Authentication, web Ekyc, reporting, etc

Tech Stack: java, spring boot, REST, mysql, aws, kafka

Hobbies & Interests

football, trekking, music

Professional Skills

Git Expert SQL Expert

POSTGRES Intermediate
NODE.JS Intermediate
JAVASCRIPT Competent
JAVA Expert

Android Competent Spring Intermediate

JSON Expert RestfulServices. Expert

RedisCache/Hazelcast

Distributed cache Expert
OOPs Expert
OOAD Expert
Design Patterns Expert

System Design and

Architecture Intermediate

Languages

English Fluent Hindi Native kumaoni Native